gizmo5.com 2011-04-12

# Gizmo5 - Make free internet calls from your mobile phone and computer - Products - Feature

## On November 12, Gizmo5 was acquired by Google.

Read the official blog [post](http://googlevoiceblog.blogspot.com/2009/11/google-welcomes-gizmo5.html) for more information.

## Privacy Policy - Service and Site

This privacy policy is designed to assist you in understanding how Gizmo5 Technologies, Inc. the creator, operator and owner of Gizmo5 ("Gizmo5") use and safeguards Information and resources you provide in using Software and Services.

#### Explanation of Service

Gizmo5 provides the Software (Software) and manages operations of the Gizmo5 Services (Services). Software is provided to all users for free but some services may require registration in order to function. Other services may require a paid subscription to Gizmo5.

Through these services, you can register to become a user of the Gizmo5 Services and communicate with other Gizmo5 users through voice communication and/or other forms of communication. You also have the option of sharing your personal profile with other users of the Software. You can also search for other users and add them to your phonebook. You can also approve or disapprove requests from other users who wish to add you to their phonebook, whereby those users will be able to see your online status. You can also invite others to download Software and register as a Gizmo5 user. From time to time, new services may be added which improve, modify or extend the functionality of the Service.

#### Use of Information

Gizmo5 DOES NOT SELL, RENT, LOAN, TRADE, LEASE OR OTHERWISE TRANSFER ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH SOFTWARE OR SERVICE TO ANY THIRD PARTY OUTSIDE THE Gizmo5 NETWORK, WHICH NETWORK INCLUDES OUR TRUSTED PARTNERS. Gizmo5 MAY ENGAGE A THIRD PARTY IN ORDER TO CARRY OUT Gizmo5'S COMMUNICATION AND/OR MARKETING ON Gizmo5'S BEHALF AND UNDER Gizmo5'S RESPONSIBILITY. Gizmo5 WILL PROVIDE INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH THE NETWORK TO OTHER USERS IN THE NETWORK ONLY WITH YOUR EXPLICIT PERMISSION AS GRANTED BY YOU THROUGH APPLICABLE SETTINGS AVAILABLE IN THE SOFTWARE. 

In the event that Gizmo5 and/or its units or subsidiaries are ever sold, acquired, merged, liquidated, reorganized, or otherwise transferred, Gizmo5 reserves the right to transfer its user databases together with any personally identifiable information contained therein, to a third-party acquiring Gizmo5.s assets. In the event Gizmo5 does so, it will place a prominent notice of the sale on the homepage of its corporate website, with links to information as to how you can change your privacy preferences.

#### What Information Do You Provide to us and How Do We Use it?

When you use the Gizmo5 Services and Software you provide three types of Information: (1) Personal Information you actively choose to disclose to the Gizmo5 Network (Active Information), (2) Usage Information that is provided passively or generated automatically during your use of Software (Passive Information) and (3) information that you share or communicate with other Software users (User Information).

Active information includes information which is required in order for the Software to verify your identity and provide you with the Gizmo5 Services. This includes your Gizmo5 Name and password. Active information may also include any billing information you submit only if you decide to purchase Services from Gizmo5. 

If you choose to invite a friend to join Gizmo5 through either a menu option in the software or facilities available at the website www.Gizmo5.com and related pages, you will be directed to a web page and will have the possibility of adding one or more email addresses in an online form. Any information entered in this form is used to send the content to those specified email addresses. Additional terms and policies may apply for sending invitations. The Gizmo5 website may also contain feedback forms where feedback can be reported directly to Gizmo5 employees. Any and all information which is voluntarily submitted in such feedback forms are used for the purposes of reviewing this feedback and improving the Software and Services. Gizmo5 reserves the right to utilize this information for marketing purposes, for instance by displaying selected comments on its website or in other communications. 

From time to time, Gizmo5 may send you surveys or solicit your feedback. Gizmo5 uses surveys to gauge user interest in new products and premiums it may offer. Gizmo5 will ask for your feedback on site features. Gizmo5 will use the information it gathers to improve its sites and provide a more meaningful experience for its users. Gizmo5 may also use the information to alert you to offers and products of Gizmo5 in which you have expressed an interest.

User Information may be required by certain Gizmo5 Services in order for the Software to function as intended and, if so desired, for other users of the Software to communicate with you. User Information includes any information you enter in your User Profile (such as name and email address) and also includes your current online status and your IP number. As with most other communication software, other users of Software may be able to obtain your IP address.

Passive Information is limited to information that is necessary in order to provide you with the desired functionality of the Software and may include a session ID token, source and destination addressing information, and the version of the Software you are using. Passive Information is automatically generated and is used to provide you with better service or statistical information used for the purposes of detecting fraud or to block access to Gizmo5 Services according to the terms set out in the End User License Agreement.

#### No Content of Communications Collected

Gizmo5 does not collect any Contents of Communications such as calls or voicemail.

#### No Extraneous System Information Collected (No Spyware)

No information concerning your computing facilities (other than hardware attributes that uniquely identify the device upon which the Software is installed) is collected that is not related to providing Gizmo5 Services, including other installed software systems, non-service-related content, or hardware peripherals. No information about your specific computing facilities will be provided to any third party outside the Gizmo5 Network unless required by the Terms of Service for Services with which you've registered.

#### No Provision of Information to Third Parties Without Your Permission (No Adware)

Gizmo5 will not sell, rent, lease or otherwise provide Active Information to any third party except as set forth above, unless required by the Terms of Service for Services with which you.ve registered.

#### What Resources Do We Use and How Do We Use Them?

During the course of using Software, disk space, bandwidth and processing power may be utilized to provide the Gizmo5 Services to you and to communicate with other Gizmo5 users. The system has been designed so that using Gizmo5 will not interfere with the normal operations of your computer.

#### How Do We Protect Your Data, Information, and Resources?

Gizmo5 uses extremely secure technology to protect the data on your computer, any information you provide to us, and to protect the use of your computer resources. The data contained in your public profile is protected and can only be shared to other users if you chose to make such information public in the software settings. Passive Information you provide is stored on secure databases. Your computer resources cannot be accessed by any third party through Software.

#### Software Installation

Software is installed on computers with an installer downloaded from www.Gizmo5.com or in combination with other software or web sites. Gizmo5 Services may also be provided through other applications that utilize the Software. These applications are required to display the Gizmo5 End User License Agreement before the Software is installed. You can uninstall the Software from the standard system Control Panel at any time.

#### Software Updates

The Software contains update functionality. This enables the Software to determine that there is a newer version available, which has improved or new functionality and/or bug fixes. You will be asked for your permission before an update is performed unless you have specifically authorized Gizmo5 to automatically update the Software without notification. The Software may however update non-program files from time to time without asking you. These updates are only used to update file indices, configurations and other non-critical objects. These updates only pertain to executable files.

#### Children

No part of the Software is directed to children. We will never knowingly collect information from users under the age of 13.

#### Delete/Deactivation Policy

If you wish to delete any personal Information you submitted to Gizmo5 Technologies, Inc, you may do so by contacting us at delete@gizmo5.com. We will notify you of our receipt of your request. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to functionally delete all such information (excluding any information necessary in order to detect fraudulent use) from our database within fifteen working days from the date of the receipt of your request. Please note that it may be impossible to delete a user.s entry without some residual Information because of backups and records of deletions. Gizmo5 reserves the right not to delete information in order to comply with applicable local laws or regulations.

#### Links

Some links of the Website will let you leave the Website and access another website. Linked websites are not under the control of Gizmo5 and it is possible that these websites have a different privacy policy. The Privacy Policy applies solely to personal information that is acquired on the Website, so Gizmo5 urges you to be careful when you enter any personal information online. Gizmo5 accepts no responsibility or liability for these other websites.

#### Risks and Disclaimers

Please be careful and responsible whenever you.re online. If you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. While we strive to protect your personal Information, Gizmo5 cannot ensure or warrant the security of any Information you transmit to us except for information specifically covered by Gizmo5.s End User License Agreement or Privacy Policy. The use of Software and Services is done at your own risk. 

Gizmo5 shall take appropriate technical measures to protect the confidentiality of the communications via its Software and Service, with due observance of the applicable obligations and exceptions under the relevant legislation.

Please be informed that, notwithstanding the above mentioned, Gizmo5 will endeavor to provide all necessary assistance and information to fulfill the request of any designated competent authority.

#### Use From Outside the United States

If you are visiting this website or using Gizmo5 from outside of the United States, please be advised that your information will be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our central database is operated. The data protection and other laws the United States and other countries, might not be as comprehensive as those in your country. Please be assured that we seek to take reasonable steps to ensure that your privacy is protected. By using our software and services, you consent to the transfer of your information to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Privacy Policy.

#### Modification of Privacy Policy.

Gizmo5 reserves the right to modify the provisions of this Privacy Policy if deemed necessary. We will inform you of these changes on our website. You agree that by continuing to use the Gizmo5 Software or Services following the publishing of the revised Privacy Policy indicates your acceptance of this Privacy Policy.

#### Contact Information

For more Information please contact us.

Effective Date of Current Policy: November 22, 2006

back to the top
